所有观测站，读取最终读数
All observation stations, take final readings.
这是我们最后一次绕轨运行
This is our last orbit.
史波克，有回应吗？
Spock. Any answers?
我还是在星球表面读到了碳循环生命体的迹象，舰长
I still read a suggestion of carbon-cycle life forms on the planet surface, Captain.
以那里的条件，在科学上是不可能的
Which is scientifically impossible under conditions there.
同意
Agreed.
苏鲁先生，切换到我正在观察的星球区域
Mr. Sulu, switch to the planet area I have under observation.
正在读取，史波克先生
I'm reading it now, Mr. Spock.
似乎表明人工能量正以系数7的数量产生
It seems to indicate artificial power being generated in factor 7 quantities.
这表明那里有相当可观的文明
Which would indicate a considerable civilization there.
你在说什么星球上有生命体的胡话，史波克？
What's all this poppycock about life forms on this planet, Spock?
表面是熔岩
The surface is molten lava.
大气有毒
The atmosphere is poisonous.
我们的读数可能有误，舰长
Our readings could be false, Captain,
也许是由某些自然现象引起
perhaps caused by some natural phenomena.
我想星际舰队应该忘记那些老旧的太空传奇
I think Starfleet should forget about those old space legends.
这里没有智慧生命
There's no intelligent life here.
上尉，有没有来自星球的消息？
Lieutenant, anything from the planet?
我反复尝试了每一个呼叫频率，长官
I repeatedly tried on every hailing frequency, sir.
所有频道都没有回应
There's no response on any channel.
将该星球的传感器读数和日志条目传给星际舰队
Transmit to Starfleet our sensor readings and log entries on the planet.
地表条件使我们无法传送下去进行调查
Surface conditions make it impossible for us to beam down and investigate.
因此我们将继续我们的下一个任务
We are therefore going on to our next assignment.
正在完成最后一圈绕轨运行，长官
Completing final orbit, sir.
准备以曲速脱离轨道
Prepare to warp us out.
[引擎故障]
[ENGINES FAIL]
警报状态
Alert status.
我们正在被扫描，舰长
We're being scanned, Captain.
深入的探测，令人难以置信地迅速
A deep probe, incredibly swift.
吉姆
Jim.
我想你是柯克舰长
Captain Kirk, I believe.
很高兴认识你，长官
A pleasure to make your acquaintance, sir.
乌乎拉…
Uhura...
无需检查你的语音电报设备
No need to check your voice-telegraph device.
我猜你认得出我吧？
Do I gather that you recognize me?
我认识你看起来的样子
I recognize what you appear to be.
外表最具有欺骗性
And appearances can be most deceiving,
但这次不是，詹姆斯·柯克
but not in this case, James Kirk.
我是亚伯拉罕·林肯
I am Abraham Lincoln.
[柯克]宇宙，最后的边疆
[KIRK] Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its fiveyear mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
星际旅行：原初
第三季第二十二集
野蛮的帷幕
The Savage Curtain
史波克
Spock.
真有趣
Fascinating.
人们用各种方式描述我，史波克先生
I have been described in many ways, Mr. Spock,
但从来没有用过这个词
but never with that word.
我在请求你的分析，史波克
I was requesting your analysis, Spock.
他们确实扫描了我们和我们的船只，舰长
They did scan us and our vessel, Captain,
并且无疑获得了足够的信息来呈现这种错觉
and doubtless obtained sufficient information to present this illusion.
幻觉？
Illusion?
舰长，你允许我登上你的船吗？
Captain, will you permit me to come aboard your vessel?
毫无疑问，你有可以检查我真实性的设备
No doubt you have devices which can check my reality.
我们很荣幸能邀请你上船，总统先生
We'd be... honored to have you aboard, Mr. President.
你们还在用分钟来衡量时间吗？
Do you still measure time in minutes?
我们可以转换成它，长官
We can convert to it, sir.
那么你会位于我的正上方在…
Then you should be directly over my position in...
那里
There.
正好十二分半
Exactly twelve and one half minutes,
到那时，舰长
Until then, Captain.
谢谢，穆尔尼先生
Thank you, Mr. Mulney.
那里发生了一点变化，舰长
Small change occurring there, Captain.
放大倍数4，舵手
Magnification 4, helm.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
面积约1000平方公里
An area of approximately 1000 square kilometers.
它的测量结果完全类似于地球
It measures completely Earth-like.
完美的氮氧大气，长官
Perfect oxygen-nitrogen atmosphere, sir.
他精确到了秒，长官
He called it to the second, sir.
我们将恰好在十二分钟后到达其上方
We'll be over it in exactly 12 minutes now.
警卫，立刻派警卫部队去传送室
Security, send a detachment to the transporter room immediately,
随身携带相位枪
phaser side arms,
并准备提供总统待遇
and be prepared to give presidential honors.
吉姆，你真的相信他是亚伯拉罕·林肯吗？
Jim, do you really believe he's Abraham Lincoln?
很明显他相信
It's obvious he believes it.
哦，麦考伊医生，斯科特先生，穿全套制服
Oh, Dr. McCoy, Mr. Scott, full dress uniforms.
全套制服？总统待遇？
Full dress? Presidential honors?
你在说什么乱七八糟的，迪克森先生
What is this nonsense, Mr. Dickerson?
我听说林肯总统要上船，长官
I understand President Lincoln's coming aboard, sir.
哦，你真傻，小伙子
Oh, you're daft, man.
舰长是这么跟我说的，长官
All I know, sir, is what the captain tells me,
他说，谁要是敢笑，他就剥了谁的皮
and he says he'll have the hide of the first man who so much as smiles.
我本以为船上的外科医生至少会保持理智！
I'd have expected sanity from the ship's surgeon, at least!
确实是林肯总统
President Lincoln indeed.
毫无疑问，紧随其后的是法国的路易和罗伯特一世
No doubt to be followed by Louis of France and Robert the Bruce.
如果真是这样，我们将对每个人给出合适的待遇，斯科特先生
If so, we'll execute appropriate honors to each, Mr. Scott.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
先生们，我一点也不相信
Gentlemen, I don't for a moment believe that
林肯总统真的会上船
President Lincoln is actually coming aboard,
但我们正在面对一种未知且看来高度先进的生命体
but we're dealing with an unknown and apparently highly advanced life form.
在我们弄清楚前…
Until we know...
我们入乡随俗
when in Rome, we'll do as the Romans do.
契科夫[对讲机]：舰桥呼叫传送室
CHEKOV [ON INTERCOM] : Bridge to transporter room.
还有一分钟到达上空位置
One minute to overhead position.
锁定了什么东西
Locked onto something.
那看起来像人类吗，史波克先生？
Does that appear human to you, Mr. Spock?
真有趣
Fascinating.
某一瞬间，它看起来几乎是矿物
For a moment, it appeared almost mineral.
像有沉重前爪的活的石头
Like living rock with heavy fore claws.
现在已经稳定下来，完全是人的读数了
It's settling down now to completely human readings.
我们现在可以随时将它传送到上船，长官
We can beam it aboard any time now, sir.
麦考伊医生，记录三录仪读数
Dr. McCoy, take tricorder readings
看看它是不是人类
and see if it is human.
演奏鼓号齐鸣，史波克先生
Appropriate ruffles and flourishes, Mr. Spock.
警卫，做好准备
Security, stand ready.
相位枪小队，准备好重度击晕
Phaser team, set ready for heavy stun.
乐队荣誉准备就绪，舰长
Band honors ready, Captain.
传送
Energize.
[船员吹口哨]
[CREWMAN BLOWS WHISTLE]
[击鼓声和号声]
[DRUM ROLL AND FANFARE]
联邦星舰企业号很荣幸能邀请你上船，总统先生
The USS Enterprise is honored to have you aboard, Mr. President.
奇怪
Strange.
演奏者们在哪里？
Where are the musicians?
那是录制的音乐，长官
That's taped music, sir.
执行任务的星舰从不带仪仗队
A starship on active duty never carries an honor detachment.
你说的是录制的音乐
Taped music, you say.
嗯，也许史波克先生稍后会好心地给我解释
Well, perhaps Mr. Spock will be good enough to explain that to me later.
一种非常有趣的登船方式，舰长
A most interesting way to come aboard, Captain.
使用的设备是什么？
What was the device used?
一个能量-物质扰频器，长官
An energy-matter scrambler, sir.
你体内的分子被转化为能量
The molecules in your body are converted into energy,
然后传送到这间屋子里，并重新转化为原来的形式
then beamed into this chamber and reconverted back into their original pattern.
好吧，既然我在这里…
Well, since I'm obviously here...
而且很完整
and quite whole,
不管你的意思是什么，显然很有效
whatever you mean apparently works very well indeed.
先生们，如果这些是武器，请放下吧
Gentlemen, if those are weapons, please lower them.
以我这个年纪，恐怕没有什么危险性
At my age, I'm afraid I'm not very dangerous.
是人类，吉姆
Human, Jim.
从里到外都是人类，麦考伊医生
All too human, Dr. McCoy.
很高兴认识你，先生
Happy to make your acquaintance, sir.
总统先生，请允许我介绍我的人员
Mr. President, may I present my officers.
史波克中校，副指挥官
Commander Spock, second in command,
轮机长斯科特和警卫官迪克森
Engineering Officer Scott and Security Officer Dickerson.
史波克先生，斯科特先生，迪克森先生
Mr. Spock, Mr. Scott, Mr. Dickerson.
先生们，我希望与你们每一个人交谈
Gentlemen, I hope to talk to each of you.
但同时，你们的舰长被问题所困扰
But meanwhile, your captain is consumed with questions
我将尽我所能地回答
and I shall do my utmost to answer them.
我相信你们的职责会腾出时间来回答我的一些问题
And I trust your duties will permit time to answer some of mine.
为您效劳，舰长
At your service, Captain.
迪克森上尉，你和你的人可以回宿舍了
Lieutenant Dickerson, you and your men may return to quarters.
总统先生
Mr. President.
一艘非常有趣的船
A most interesting vessel.
在你把他传送上船前，你锁定的是什么？
Just what was it you locked onto before you beamed him aboard?
你听到了史波克先生说的
You heard Mr. Spock yourself.
他称之为矿物，就像活的石头
Mineral, he called it. Like living rock.
那变成了林肯？
And that became Lincoln?
我说不清
I couldn't tell.
可能是另一个人在那里站着
May have been another figure down there standing by.
你怎么看？
What do you make of it?
我不太确定
I'm not quite sure.
柯克：舰长日志，星历5906.4
KIRK: Captain's log, stardate 5906.4.
我们传送了谁或是什么东西上了船？
Who or what has been beamed aboard our vessel?
一个把自己变成这种形态的外星人？一个幻象？
An alien who has changed himself into this form? An illusion?
我无法想象亚伯拉罕·林肯
I cannot conceive it possible that Abraham Lincoln
有可能真的转世了
could have actually been reincarnated.
然而他的仁慈，他的温柔智慧，他的幽默
And yet his kindness, his gentle wisdom, his humor,
关于他的一切都是那么真实
everything about him is so right.
如果我没记错，你们联邦军队的观测气球大约在600英尺高的地方
Yes, if I recall, your Union Army observation balloons were tendered 600 or so feet high.
我们在这个星球表面上方643英里处
We're 643 miles above the surface of this planet.
你们能把这么长的距离测量得那么精确吗？
You can measure great distances that closely?
我们可以，长官
We do, sir.
目前高度，643英里2,021英尺2.04英寸
643 miles, 2,021 feet, 2.04 inches, at this moment,
使用你的旧式测量单位的话
using your old style measurements.
保佑我
Bless me.
打扰一下，柯克舰长
Excuse me, Captain Kirk.
你说
Yes?
斯科特先生…
Mr. Scott...
多么迷人的黑人女性啊
What a charming Negress.
哦，原谅我，亲爱的
Oh, forgive me, my dear.
我知道在我那个时代，有些人用这个词来描述财产
I know in my time some used that term as a description of property.
但我为什么要反对这个词呢，长官？
But why should I object to that term, sir?
在我们这个世纪，我们已经学会了不惧怕语言
See in our century, we've learned not to fear words.
请让我介绍我们的通讯官，乌乎拉上尉
May I present our communications officer, Lieutenant Uhura.
我那个世纪的愚昧
The foolishness of my century
让我在没有冒犯的情况下道歉
had me apologizing where no offense was given.
我们每个人都学会了以做自己为荣
We've each learned to be delighted with what we are.
瓦肯人比我们早几个世纪就学会了
The Vulcans learned that centuries before we did.
它是瓦肯哲学的基础，长官
It is basic to the Vulcan philosophy, sir.
让存在变得有价值的一系列事物的组合
The combination of a number of things to make existence worthwhile.
是的
Yes,
"诺姆"的哲学，意思是“全部”
Philosophy of "Nome," meaning all.
我是怎么知道的？
How did I know that?
就像我似乎知道在星球表面
Just as I seem to know that on the planet's surface,
你将见到一位瓦肯人，他在你们星球历史上是最伟大的人物之一
you will meet one of the greatest living Vulcans in all the long history of your planet.
我的脑子里想不起来他的名字
My mind cannot recall his name,
但我知道他会在那里
but I know he will be there.
是什么给你的船提供动力，舰长？
What is it that powers your vessel, Captain?
我可以看看你的轮机室吗？
May I see your engine room?
当然，我们的轮机长…
Certainly. Our engineering officer...
已经在简报室等了你两个多小时了，长官
Has been waiting in the briefing room for you, sir, for over two hours.
哦，天哪
Oh, dear.
请原谅我，我们的通讯官…
If you'll forgive me, our communications officer...
我很高兴让她当向导
I would be delighted to have her as a guide.
再次原谅我
Forgive me again.
我们很快就回来
We'll rejoin you shortly.
他们到底在哪儿？
Where the devil are they?
他们可能正在厨房里找一盘羊杂碎
They're probably looking up a plate of haggis in the galley.
其他地方他们都去过了
They've been everywhere else.
抱歉耽误了，先生们
Sorry to have been delayed, gentlemen.
吉姆，我是最后一个对你的指挥形象提出建议的…
Jim, I would be the last to advise you on your command image...
我怀疑，老骨头，但请继续
I doubt that, Bones, but continue.
一定要我明说吗？
Do I have to lay it out for you?
几乎所有船员都看到你把这个骗子者当作真的对待
Practically the entire crew has seen you treat this impostor like the real thing...
然而他不可能是真的
when he can't possibly be the real article.
三百年前林肯就死在了离这上百光年的一颗星球上
Lincoln died three centuries ago on a planet hundreds of light-years away.
应该是那个方向，轮机长
More that direction, Engineer.
你是科学官，你为何不
You're the science officer. Why aren't you,
呃，在这个时候做些科学官们做的事？
well, doing whatever a science officer does at a time like this?
我是，医生，我在观察外星人
I am, Doctor. I am observing the alien.
终于，至少有人同意我们的看法了
At last. At least somebody agrees with us.
他是个外星人
He's an alien.
他当然是个外星人
Yes, of course, he's an alien.
他有潜在危险
He's potentially dangerous.
疯了！和大角星犬鸟一样疯！
Mad! Loony as an Arcturian dog bird!
先生们，如你们所知，史波克先生和我已被邀请
Gentlemen, as you know, Mr. Spock and I have been invited
和他一起传送到星球表面
to beam down to the planet's surface with him.
有什么意见吗？
Any comments on that?
是的，很大
Yes, a big one.
突然间，奇迹般地
Suddenly, miraculously,
我们看到那里有一小块类似地球的环境
we see a small spot of earth-type environment down there.
它真的在那里还是只是我们认为我们看到它在那里？
Is it really there or do we just think we see it down there?
你们可能会传送到熔岩的海洋里
You might beam down into a sea of molten lava.
但他为什么只想杀我们两个？
But why would he want to kill only two of us?
这不合逻辑
It would be illogical.
有了这样的能力，他们可以很容易地骗我们摧毁整艘船
With such abilities, they could as easily trick us into destroying the entire vessel.
史波克先生，你是在暗示
Are you implying, Mr. Spock,
传送去那里可能是安全的吗？
that it's probably safe to beam down there?
不，我没有，医生
No, I'm not, Doctor.
毫无疑问，他们希望我们去那里是有不可告人的目的
There's no doubt they want us down there for a hidden purpose.
否则，他们就会为这一切提供一些合乎逻辑的理由
Otherwise, they would have revealed some logical reason for all of this.
为什么是林肯，史波克？对此有什么猜测吗？
Why Lincoln, Spock? Any speculation on that?
猜测是不必要的，舰长，答案很明显
Speculation is unnecessary, Captain. The answer is clear.
对你来说林肯总统一直是一个非常个人化的英雄
President Lincoln has always been a very personal hero to you.
有什么能比让他活灵活现地出现在你面前
What better way to titillate your curiosity
更能激起你的好奇心呢？
than to make him come alive for you.
不仅是我，史波克
And not only to me, Spock.
同意
Agreed.
我也感受到了他的魅力
I, too, experienced his charm.
这是一件令人印象深刻的复制品
It is a magnificent work of duplication.
但他与你有着特殊的关系，吉姆
But he holds a special involvement to you, Jim.
而且我认为很有趣的是
And I think it's interesting,
你是决定是否传送下去的人
in as much as you're the one who's going to make the decision whether to beam down or not.
别这么做，舰长
Don't do it, Captain.
我们的星舰存在的意义就是与其他生命接触
The very reason for the existence of our starships is contact with other life.
尽管我们无法理解这个方法
Although the method is beyond our comprehension,
但有人给我们提供了接触的机会
we have been offered contact.
因此，我将传送下去
Therefore, I shall beam down.
至于你，史波克先生…
Mr. Spock, as for you...
舰长，既然我被包括在邀请中
Captain, since I was included in the invitation,
我必须和你一起传送下去
I must beam down with you.
你俩都疯了！
You're both out of your heads!
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
你是要违抗命令吗！
And you're on the edge of insubordination!
我提醒舰长
Would I be on the edge of insubordination to remind the captain
发生在他身上的潜在伤害
this smells of something happening to him
我可能无法挽救是违抗命令？
that I might not be able to patch back together again?
是的！
Aye!
先生们，我已记下并感谢你们的关心
Gentlemen, your concern is noted and appreciated.
史波克先生，标准制服，三录仪和相位枪
Mr. Spock, standard dress, tricorders and phasers.
我们将引导林肯总统去传送室
We will guide President Lincoln to the transporter room.
我们会马上传送下去
We'll beam down immediately.
待命，斯科特先生
Standing by, Mr. Scott.
传送室呼叫舰桥，待命
Transporter room to bridge, standing by.
契科夫[通过对讲机]：我们现在锁定在同步轨道上，斯科特先生
CHEKOV [OVER INTERCOM] :  We are now locked in synchronous orbit, Mr. Scott.
传感器继续显示该地区在各方面都完全类似于地球
Sensors continue to show the area as completely Earth-like in all respects.
如果他们错了，他们真的传送进了熔岩池…
If they are wrong and they do beam into a pool of lava...
那他们就死了
Then they're dead men.
我无法及时将它们拉回来
I couldn't pull them back in time.
好了，斯科特先生，传送
All right, Mr. Scott. Energize.
斯科提！
Scotty!
[史波克]舰长
[SPOCK] Captain.
我们的相位枪和三录仪没有和我们一起传送下来
Our phasers and tricorder did not beam down with us.
柯克呼叫企业号，企业号？
Kirk to Enterprise. Enterprise?
企业号，请回答
Enterprise. Come in.
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
企业号，请回答
Enterprise, come in.
没有坏，但有东西在影响它们工作
Undamaged, yet something is preventing them from functioning.
请回答，登陆小队，报告
Come in, landing party. Report.
企业号呼叫柯克舰长
Enterprise to Captain Kirk.
你能听到我们吗？
Can you read us?
如果他们没事，他们应该回复的
If they're all right, they should have reported in.
你的解释，长官？
Your explanation, sir?
我没有
I have none.
对我来说，这似乎是很正常的
To me this seems quite as it should be.
为什么我们的武器会被拿走？
Why were our weapons taken?
为什么我们不能和飞船通信？
Why can't we communicate with our ship?
请相信我
Please, believe me.
除了我告诉你的，我什么都不知道
I know nothing other than what I told you.
游戏结束了
The game's over.
我们以礼相待
We've treated you with courtesy.
我们已经顺着你的想法和你的身份走了
We've gone along with what and who you think you are.
尽管有看似矛盾的地方，一切都如其所见
Despite the seeming contradictions, all is as it appears to be.
我是亚伯拉罕·林肯
I am Abraham Lincoln.
正如我看起来像谁
Just as I am whom I appear to be.
苏拉克
Surak.
谁？
Who?
我们星球上有史以来最伟大的人，舰长
The greatest of all who ever lived on our planet, Captain.
我们的一切的奠基者
The father of all we became.
飞船所有的系统都停止运行了
All ship's systems going dead.
切换到备用电源
Switch to reserve power.
所有甲板，报告状态
All decks, report status.
舰桥呼叫轮机部
Bridge to engineering.
请回答，我们的动力怎么了？
Come in. What's happening to our power?
舰桥呼叫轮机部，报告
Bridge to Engineering, report.
轮机手 [通过对讲机]：所有设备都罢工了
ENGINEER [OVER INTERCOM] : Everything's out.
我们已经切换到备用电源
We've switched to reserve power.
曲速引擎失去所有动力
Lost all power in the warp engines.
怎么样，苏鲁先生？
How is it, Mr. Sulu?
目前还没不清楚是什么原因，他们正在待命
No answer yet on what caused it. They're standing by.
关闭所有不必要的系统
Shut down all but the most necessary systems.
没有损坏报告，斯科特先生
No damage report, Mr. Scott.
没有发动机损坏的迹象，长官
No indication of engine damage, sir.
启动重启周期
Engage restart cycle.
不行
I can't.
开始应急程序
Start emergency procedures.
Aye, aye, sir.
是的，长官
生生不息，繁荣昌盛，史波克
Live long and prosper, Spock.
你也是，柯克舰长
May you also, Captain Kirk.
你是苏拉克是不合逻辑的
It is not logical that you are Surak.
没有任何事实、对事实的推断或理论，可以使...
There is no fact, extrapolation of fact, or theory, which makes possible...
不管我是什么，做出回应会伤害你吗？
Whatever I am, would it harm you to give response?
生生不息，繁荣昌盛，苏拉克的形象
Live long and prosper, image of Surak,
我们现在拥有的一切的奠基者
father of all we now hold true.
苏拉克的形象从你的脸上读出了你的想法，史波克
The image of Surak read in your face what is in your mind, Spock.
当我转过身来，眼睛看到你时，我流露出了情感
As I turned and my eyes beheld you, I displayed emotion.
我请求原谅
I beg forgiveness.
原因就更充分了
The cause was more than sufficient.
我们不要再谈这个了
Let us speak no further of it.
在我那个时代，我们不知道地球人
In my time, we knew not of Earthmen.
我很高兴看到我们有差异
I am pleased to see that we have differences.
愿我们二人同心，其利断金
May we together become greater than the sum of both of us.
史波克，我们别再和他玩这些猜谜游戏了
Spock, we'll not go along with these charades any longer.
你很快就会有答案的，舰长
You will have an answer soon, Captain.
我们的世界被称为埃斯卡比亚
Our world is called Excalbia.
无数住在那个星球上的人都在观看
Countless who live on that planet are watching.
好戏开始之前
Before this drama unfolds,
我们欢迎柯克和史波克
we give welcome to the ones named Kirk and Spock.
我们对你们的世界或习俗一无所知
We know nothing of your world, or your customs.
“好戏即将开始”是什​​么意思？
What do you mean "drama about to unfold"?
你们是智慧生命体
You're intelligent life forms.
我很惊讶你没有意识到我们给你的荣誉
I am surprised you do not perceive the honor we do you.
我们不是我们星球上创造了一个与你们自己的世界相同的舞台吗？
Have we not created in this place on our planet a stage identical to your own world?
我们认为我们是被邀请来这里的，我们是为了友谊而来
We perceive that we were invited here and we came in friendship
你夺走了我们调查你们的世界
and you have deprived us of our instruments to examine your world,
保卫我们自己，与我们的船只沟通的工具
to defend ourselves, to communicate with our vessel.
你的意见已采纳
Your objection is well taken.
我们将与你的船只沟通
We shall communicate with your vessel
以便你们的同胞也能享受并从这出戏中获益
so that your fellow life forms may also enjoy and profit from the play.
看吧
Behold.
舰长，史波克先生，你可能通过历史知道其中一些
Captain, Mr. Spock, some of these you may know through history.
比如，成吉思汗
Genghis Khan, for one.
格林上校，在21世纪初在地球上领导了一场种族灭绝战争
And Colonel Green, who led a genocidal war early in the 21st century on Earth.
佐拉，她在蒂伯龙上对被统治部落进行了身体化学实验
Zora, who experimented with the body chemistry of subject tribes on Tiburon.
难忘的凯勒斯
Kahless the Unforgettable,
为他的星球的暴政树立典范的克林贡人
the Klingon who set the pattern for his planet's tyrannies.
我们欢迎企业号飞船来到我们的太阳系和我们的精彩表演
We welcome the vessel Enterprise to our solar system and to our spectacle.
至少舰长和史波克是安全的
At least the captain and Spock are safe.
这是某种形式的对抗
It's a confrontation of some sort.
这些都是历史上的人物
Those are figures out of history.
臭名昭著的恶人
Notoriously evil.
我们请你与我们一起观察
We ask you to observe with us
你称之为“善与恶”的两种对立哲学的对抗
the confrontation of the two opposing philosophies you term "good and evil".
由于这是我们对地球人的第一次实验，我们的主题很简单
Since this is our first experiment with Earthlings, our theme's a simple one
生存，生与死
survival, life and death.
我们对你们的理念很陌生
Your philosophies are alien to us.
我们希望了解它们，弄清楚哪个更强大
We wish to understand them and discover which is the stronger.
我们通过观察这样的表演来学习
We learn by observing such spectacles.
你说的“生存”是什么意思？
What do you mean "survival"?
意思很明确
The word is explicit.
如果你和史波克幸存下来，你们会返回你的船
If you and Spock survive, you return to your vessel.
如果你们没有…
If you do not...
…你们就不存在了
...your existence is ended.
我们可以把舰长和史波克传送回来吗？
Can we beam the captain and Spock back up?
我们没有动力，传送回来的会是一堆死肉
We don't have the power. They'll come aboard a mass of dying flesh.
我们可以把相位枪送下去吗？
Can we send the phasers down?
我们无能为力，医生
There's nothing we can do, Doctor.
只能看着他们
Nothing but watch them.
他选了历史上最坏的几个人来对付他们
He's skimmed the worst ones in history to face them.
但他们不是真的
But they're not real.
不仅仅是林肯或苏拉克
Any more than that Lincoln or Surak.
传感器读到什么？
What do the sensors read?
生命体
As life forms.
他们是生物
They are living beings.
他们会不会是外星人，投射出的幻象？
Could they be aliens, projecting an illusion?
读数是类人生物的读数
The readings are those of humanoids.
你为什么犹豫？
Why do you hesitate?
你想要进一步说明吗？
Do you wish further clarification?
你的行动选择是无限的，你选择的武器也是如此
Your choice of action is unlimited, as is your choice of weapons.
如果你想用什么东西
Should you wish to use any,
你可以用你周围能找到的东西制造出你想要的
you may fabricate anything you desire out of what you can find around you,
舰长？
Captain?
史波克先生和我拒绝参加
Mr. Spock and I refuse to participate.
你会做出其他决定的
You will decide otherwise.
分析，史波克
Analysis, Spock.
他们为什么想让我们打架？
Why do they want us to fight?
也许就像他解释的，舰长
It may be exactly as explained, Captain.
我们的善恶观念对他们来说很陌生
Our concept of good and evil is strange to them.
也许他们想确定哪个最强
Perhaps they wish to determine which is strongest.
如果杀死我们，他们就会得到答案
And they'll get their answers if it kills us.
恐怕我们没人能离开，先生们
I'm afraid none of us may leave, gentlemen,
除非我们按照它的要求做
until we do what it demands of us.
柯克舰长
Captain Kirk,
我可以和你谈谈吗？
may I speak with you?
我非常同意你对这出戏的态度
I quite agree with your attitude toward this charade.
认为我们应该参与太可笑了
It's ridiculous to think we should take part in it.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
和你一样，离开这里
The same thing as you do, to get out of here.
我和你没有任何争执，就像你和我一样
I have no quarrel with you, any more than you have with me.
你与历史对你的描述有些不同，格林上校
You're somewhat different than the way history paints you, Colonel Green.
历史往往夸大其词
History tends to exaggerate.
我建议我们立即叫停
I suggest we call a halt to this at once
看看我们是否能找到摆脱困境的方法
and see if we can't find some way out of our difficulties.
我的伙伴们完全同意我的看法
My associates are in full agreement with me.
舰长，你是被骗来这里的，是吗？
Captain, you were tricked into coming here, weren't you?
我们也都是
So were we all.
你从哪里来的？
Where do you come from?
我不记得了
I can't remember.
这不奇怪吗？
Isn't that strange?
我的记忆力原来非常好
My memory used to be quite remarkable.
嗯，不管在哪里，我都想回去
Well, wherever it was, I want to get back.
所以在我看来，舰长
So it seems to me, Captain,
我们有一个共同的想法
that we have a common cause,
我们的敌人是那个生物
and our enemy is that creature.
你有什么建议？
What do you propose?
[格林]就是我们结合力量，推理出一些方法来战胜它
[Green] That we combine forces and reason some way to overcome it.
格林上校，你臭名昭著
You were notorious, Colonel Green,
是因为在与敌人谈判的过程中打击他们
for striking at your enemies in the midst of negotiating with them.
但那是几个世纪以前的事了，舰长，而且并不完全是真的
But that was centuries ago, Captain, and not altogether true.
不，如果可以的话，我现在想改变的地方很多
No, there's much I would change now, if I could.
不要让偏见和谣言左右你
Don't let prejudice and rumor sway you.
舰长！
Captain!
我们如何警告他？
How can we warn him?
有人受伤了吗？
Anyone hurt?
我担心我的衣服有些破损
I fear my clothing is somewhat damaged,
但以我的年龄还能摔跤是多么令人高兴
but how delightful to discover at my age that I can still wrestle.
史波克先生？
Mr. Spock?
我很好，舰长
I'm all right, Captain.
但是，我建议我们为下一次攻击做好准备
However, I suggest that we prepare ourselves for another attack.
不，我认为格林上校是对的
No. I think Colonel Green is right.
那石头一样的东西是我们的敌人
That rock-like thing is our enemy,
不是那些幻象
not those illusions.
作为幻象，刚刚那可是结结实实的一拳
For an illusion, my opponent carried a considerable punch.
我忘了，你认为我也是幻象
I forgot. You consider me an illusion, too.
舰长说得很有道理
The captain speaks wisely.
那四个人不是我们的敌人
Those four are not our enemy.
我们应该共同达成一个和平的解决方案
We should arrive together at a peaceful settlement.
我很失望
I am disappointed.
你毫不在意我们给你的荣誉
You display no interest in the honor we do you.
我们为你提供成为我们老师的机会
We offer you an opportunity to become our teachers
通过证明善与恶哪个更强大
by demonstrating whether good or evil is more powerful.
你觉得我的体热令人痛苦吗，舰长？
You find my body heat distressing, Captain?
你忘记了这个星球的本质
You forget the nature of this planet.
我必须断定，你们需要一个战斗的理由
I must conclude that your species requires a cause to fight for.
你现在可以与你的船进行通信
You may now communicate with your ship.
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
企业号，请回答
Enterprise, come in.
[斯科特]斯科特呼叫轮机部，报告，上尉
[SCOTT] Scott to Engineering. Report, Lieutenant.
[轮机手]紧急情况变严重，长官
[ENGINEER] Emergency increasing, sir.
恶化刚刚开始， 长官
Deterioration has just started, sir.
再说一遍，我听不见你说的
Give me that again, man. I cannot hear you.
斯科特先生，我有舰长的消息
Mr. Scott, I have the captain.
斯科提，你能听到我吗？
Scotty, do you read me?
斯科特先生，我有舰长的消息
Mr. Scott, I have the captain.
轮机部，检查辐射
Engineering, check for radiation.
马上找个维修工去
Get a repair crew on it at once.
已经找了，长官，似乎无法阻止
We have already, sir. We can't seem to stop it.
有爆炸危险吗？
Is there a danger of detonation?
估计四个小时，长官
Estimating four hours, sir.
红色警报，舰长，斯科特先生正在待命
Red Alert, Captain. Mr. Scott is standing by.
[柯克]为什么拉红色警报？
[KIRK] What caused the red alert?
我还不知道，长官
I don't know yet, sir.
舰长
Captain.
斯科提，快点把我们传送上去
Scotty, beam us up fast.
我不能
I cannot.
我们有动力故障
We have a power failure.
我们现在只有应急电池供电
We're on emergency battery power only.
发生了什么？
What happened?
我无法解释，长官
I can't explain it, sir,
但是物质和反物质在红色区域附近
but the matter and antimatter are in red zone proximity.
是什么原因造成的？
What caused that?
没有人知道，也没有人可以阻止
There's no knowing and there's no stopping it either.
护盾正在失效
The shielding is breaking down.
我估计还有四个小时完全失效
I estimate four hours before it goes completely.
还有四个小时飞船就会爆炸
Four hours before the ship blows up.
估计非常正确
The estimate is quite correct.
你的飞船会在四个小时内把自己炸成碎片，舰长
Your ship will blow itself to bits within four hours, Captain,
除非你在那之前打败其他人
unless you defeat the others before then.
这个理由足以为之而战了吧？
Is that cause enough to fight for?
如果他们打败了我们怎么办？
What if they defeat us?
要拯救你的飞船和船员
To save your ship and your crew,
你必须赢
you have to win.
斯科提，通知星际舰队指挥部
Scotty, inform Starfleet Command.
脱离引擎舱，如果可能的话，减少负重
Disengage nacelles, Jettison if possible.
史波克先生，帮助他们，提供建议并进行分析
Mr. Spock, assist them. Advise and analyse.
斯科提？
Scotty?
你的通讯器失效了，舰长
Your communicators no longer function, Captain.
你可以继续看表演
You may proceed with the spectacle.
詹姆斯，战争是强加给我们的
James, the war is forced upon us.
历史总是重演
History repeats itself.
斯科特：补充日志，星历5906.5
SCOTT: Supplemental log, stardate 5906.5.
轮机长斯科特报告
Engineer Scott reporting.
企业号一定会在两小时内爆炸
The Enterprise is doomed to explode in two hours
如果柯克舰长被这个星球上的敌人打败了
if Captain Kirk is defeated by the enemy on the surface of the planet.
企业号的巨大力量已被化解
The enormous power of the Enterprise has been neutralised
我们只能坐在这里看，无法提供帮助
and we sit here watching, unable to assist.
你设下陷阱了吗？
Did you set the traps?
是的
Yes.
有什么发现吗？他们在干什么？
What did you find out? What are they doing?
什么都没做
They've done nothing.
他们没有武装自己，也没有准备任何防御
They've not armed themselves nor prepared for any kind of defence.
要我说现在就攻击并解决他们
I say attack now and finish them.
用什么？这些？
With what? These?
比他们的好
Better than what they have.
不，没有绝对的优势
No, it's not advantage enough.
我想确保我们有胜算
I want to make sure the odds are in our favor.
压倒和毁灭
Overwhelm and devastate,
这就是获得并保持权力的方式
that's the way to get power and to hold it,
正是我要做的
I mean to do that.
与幻象作斗争并没有什么不道德的，史波克先生
There's nothing immoral about fighting an illusion, Mr. Spock.
我们照他们的规则行动，战斗
We play their game, fight,
要不然失去飞船和所有船员
or lose the ship and all the crewmen aboard.
如果他们是真的呢，舰长？
And if they are real, Captain?
我们把这里…作为据点
We'll use this... as a base.
这是可防御的
It's defensible.
他们一靠近就会被看到
They can't approach without being seen.
我们是在打一场防御战吗，詹姆斯？
Are we fighting a defensive war, James?
不，我们没有时间
No, we don't have time.
但如果形势对我们不利，我想有个撤退的地方
But if things go against us, I want a place to retreat to.
我现在要做的是侦察他们的情况
What I want to do now is scout them out,
找到他们的弱点并发起进攻
find their weaknesses and attack.
你喝威士忌吗？
You drink whiskey?
偶尔，为什么问？
Occasionally. Why?
因为你的品质非常像一个我非常钦佩的人
Because you have qualities very much like those of another man I admire greatly.
格兰特将军
General Grant.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你
史波克先生，我们需要武器
Mr. Spock, we'll need weapons.
我想古代瓦肯人制造过类似回旋镖的东西？
I believe the ancient Vulcans made something like a boomerang?
是的，舰长
Yes, Captain.
还有吊索和长矛，吊索…
And slings and spears. Slings...
总统先生， 你小时候用过吊索
Mister President. You used a sling as a boy.
我确实用过
Indeed I did.
舰长，逻辑要求我们考虑另一条路线
Captain, logic dictates that we consider another course.
我们没有太多时间，史波克
We don't have much time, Spock.
我在瓦肯的时候，我们也面临过同样的选择
In my time on Vulcan, we also faced these same alternatives.
我们遭受了毁灭性的战争，几乎摧毁了我们的星球
We'd suffered devastating wars, which nearly destroyed our planet.
另一场战争也即将开始
Another was about to begin.
我们左右为难
We were torn.
但从我们的痛苦中，我们中的一些人找到了行动的方法
But out of our suffering, some of us found the discipline to act.
我们派使者向我们的对手提出求和
We sent emissaries to our opponents to propose peace.
先去的被杀了
The first were killed.
但后来的人跟上他
But others followed.
最终，我们实现了和平
Ultimately, we achieved peace,
并一直持续至今
which has lasted since then.
那时的情况不同了，苏拉克
Circumstances were different then, Surak.
战争的面貌从未改变，舰长
The face of war has never changed, Captain.
和解当然比杀戮更合乎逻辑
Surely it is more logical to heal than kill.
但恐怕这种逻辑在这里不适用
I'm afraid that kind of logic doesn't apply here.
这正是我们不应该战斗的原因
That is precisely why we should not fight.
我的飞船危在旦夕
My ship is at stake.
我不会伤害别人，舰长
I will not harm others, Captain.
在这件事上他的的信念是非常深远的，舰长
His convictions are most profound in this matter, Captain.
我的也是，史波克
So are mine, Spock.
如果我相信有一条和平的出路…
If I believed that there was a peaceful way out of this ...
风险将由我一人承担
This risk will be mine alone.
如果我失败了，你没有任何损失
If I fail, you lose nothing.
毕竟，我不是战士
After all, I'm no warrior.
舰长知道我以前曾和他并肩战斗
The captain knows that I have fought at his side before
如果现在有需要我还会这么做
and will do so now, if need be.
然而，我也是一个瓦肯人，为和平而生
However, I too, am a Vulcan, bred to peace.
让他试试
Let him attempt it.
你看到他们是多么奸诈了
You saw how treacherously they acted.
是的
Oh, yes.
但也许真正考验的是我们对和平的信念
But perhaps it's our belief in peace that is actually being tested.
我没有权力管你
I have no authority over you.
按你认为最好的方式做
You may do as you think best.
谢谢你
Thank you.
愿你生生不息，繁荣昌盛
May you live long and prosper.
武器，长官们
The weapons, gentlemen.
万一他失败了
In case he fails.
上校
Colonel.
不！
No!
让我们听听他怎么说
Let's hear what he has to say.
他的话可能很有用
We may find it useful.
停在那里，瓦肯人
Stop there, Vulcan.
说明你的来意
State your purpose.
我和平地来提议和平
I come in peace to propose peace.
你投降了吗？
Are you surrendering?
我这么做是为了大家好
I'm doing what I consider best for all of us.
如果你选择将其视为投降
If you choose to regard that as surrender,
我接受你的定义
I accept your definition.
那些和平爱好者之一，上校
One of those peace lovers, Colonel.
你为什么这么做？
Why are you doing this?
你代表别人说话吗？
Do you speak for the others?
不，我为自己说话，因为我厌恶暴力
No, I speak for myself because I abhor violence.
但如果你接受我提供的解决方案，他们也会接受
But if you accept the solution I offer, they, too, will accept it.
我怎么能确定？
How can I be sure?
我认为你在试图欺骗我，瓦肯人
I think you're trying to trick me, Vulcan.
我认为你在这里谈论和平时
I think that while you're here talking peace,
其他人在准备进攻
the others are preparing to attack.
不，上校，他们在据点，等待答复
No, Colonel. They are at their base, awaiting an answer.
我怎么能相信呢？
How can I believe that?
没有人会谈论和平，除非他用战争来支持和平
No one talks peace unless he's ready to back it up with war.
他会谈论和平，如果这是唯一的生活方式
He talks peace if it's the only way to live.
那么告诉我，如果我们接受，你能得到什么？
Then tell me, what do you have to gain if we accept?
我所做的只是我所相信的知识
Nothing but the knowledge that I have done what I believe in.
我能从中得到什么？
What do I get out of it?
我为利益而战，瓦肯人
I fight for gain, Vulcan.
我能在这里得到什么？
What do I gain here?
你的生命和其他人的生命
Your life and the lives of the others.
你自己说过，上校，我们的共同目标是生存
You said yourself, Colonel, that we have common cause to survive.
我们一起就能做到
Together we can.
而不是通过交战
But not by warring.
我们为什么不杀了他？
Why don't we kill him?
不
No.
他是我们解决他们所有人的方法
He's our means to finish them all.
上校，你肯定接受这样的逻辑？
Colonel, surely you accept the logic of this?
你的答案是什么？
What is your answer?
你很会说服人，瓦肯人
You're very persuasive, Vulcan.
我想安然无恙地摆脱这种情况
I'd like to come out of this with a whole skin.
也许我可以说服我的同伴
Perhaps I can convince my associates
这对他们也有好处
that it would be to their advantage also.
你的苏拉克是个勇敢的人
Your Surak is a brave man.
和平的人通常是，舰长
Men of peace usually are, Captain.
在瓦肯，他被尊为我们的文明之父
On Vulcan, he is revered as the father of our civilization.
父亲的形象对我们来说意义重大
The father image holds much meaning for us.
你表现出情感，史波克
You show emotion, Spock.
我非常尊重他所取得的成就
I deeply respect what he has accomplished.
我希望他很快在这里取得一些成就
I hope he accomplishes something here, and soon.
[尖叫]
[SCREAM]
苏拉克？
Surak?
苏拉克：帮帮我，史波克！
SURAK: Help me, Spock!
史波克，帮帮我！
Spock, help me!
格林：史波克先生，你的朋友想要你
GREEN: Mr. Spock, your friend wants you.
他好像受伤了
He seems to be hurt.
史波克
Spock!
帮帮我，史波克！
Help me, Spock!
史波克！帮帮我！
Spock! Help me!
格林：你不能让他受苦
GREEN: You can't let him suffer.
他们试图煽动我们进攻，舰长
They're trying to goad us into attacking, Captain.
他们希望我们贸然行动
They expect us to act rashly.
是的，我知道
Yes, I know that.
帮帮我，史波克！
Help me, Spock!
You had no choice, Captain.
He was aware of what might happen when he went.
我就不应该让他走
I should never have let him go.
你别无选择，舰长
You had no choice, Captain.
[尖叫]
[SCREAM]
你阻止不了他
You could not have stopped him.
你怎么能无视呢？
How can you ignore that?
瓦肯人不会这样喊叫
A Vulcan would not cry out so.
不管他是不是瓦肯人，他都处于痛苦之中
Whether he's a Vulcan or not, he's in agony.
我不是麻木不仁的，舰长
I am not insensitive to it, Captain.
帮帮我，史波克！
Help me, Spock!
但是你可以听着它而什么都不做
But you can just listen to it and do nothing.
我不能
I can't.
舰长，这就是他们想看到的
Captain, that is what they are waiting for.
他们在等我们试着营救
They're waiting for us to attempt a rescue.
我不能让他留在那里
I can't just let him stay there.
也许我们可以救他，史波克先生
Perhaps we can rescue him, Mr. Spock.
我建议我们按他们的想法去做
I suggest that we do whatever they want.
按他们的想法做，长官？
Do what they want, sir?
但不是以他们想要的方式
Not the way they want it, however.
我们必须首先让他们相信
We must first convince them
他们激怒了我们，使我们变得鲁莽
that they have provoked us to recklessness.
詹姆士，我并不是要滥用你的威信
James, I do not mean to presume upon your authority.
我的提议是我绕到他们的后方
What I propose is that I circle around to their rear,
当你们两个提供正面攻击时
while you two provide a frontal assault.
它应该足够暴力以掩护我的行动
It should be sufficiently violent to cover whatever I do.
你会怎么做？
What will you do?
我溜进他们的营地并释放他
I, slip into their camp and free him.
不行
No.
詹姆斯啊，詹姆斯
James, James.
记着，我是个乡野村夫
Remember, I was something of a backwoodsman.
我怀疑你不能做我从小就做的事情
I doubt that you could do what I was bred to.
我不能让你冒险，总统先生
I can't let you risk it, Mr. President.
我已经不是总统了
I am no longer president.
史波克先生，有什么意见吗？
Mr. Spock, any comment?
帮帮我，史波克！
Help me, Spock!
不，长官
No, sir.
还有一件事，先生们
One matter further, gentlemen.
我们要像他们一样战斗
We fight on their level.
以诡计、残暴、决绝的方式
With trickery, brutality, finality.
来匹配他们的邪恶
We match their evil.
我知道，詹姆斯
I know, James.
我被誉为一个温和的人
I was reputed to be a gentle man.
但我是总司令
But I was commander in chief
在我国历史上最血腥的四年里
during the four bloodiest years of my country's history.
我的命令让十万人死于
I gave orders that sent 100,000 men to their death
他们兄弟的手中
at the hands of their brothers.
没有光荣的杀戮
There's no honorable way to kill,
也没有温和的毁灭
no gentle way to destroy.
战争除了终结战争没有什么好处
There is nothing good in war except its ending.
你正在为你船员的生命而战
And you're fighting for the lives of your crew.
是你的战役，总统先生
Your campaign, Mr. President.
他们应该很快就会来
They should be coming soon.
佐拉！凯勒斯！
Zora! Kahless!
不，等等！
No, wait!
你看到了几个人？
How many did you see?
两个
Two.
苏拉克，其他人已经把他们引开了
Surak, the others have drawn them away.
我们会绕一圈
We will circle around.
这是一个值得的努力，苏拉克，值得的
It was a worthy effort, Surak. Worthy.
没必要因为它的失败而责怪自己
No need to blame yourself for its failure.
帮帮我，史波克
Help me, Spock.
现在你能学林肯的哭喊吗？
Now can you cry like Lincoln?
帮帮我，柯克
Help me, Kirk.
林肯先生！
Mr. Lincoln!
詹姆斯，别过来
James, stay back.
你们是幸存者
You are the survivors.
其他人都逃跑了
The others have run off.
看来，邪恶在强行对抗时就会退缩
It would seem that evil retreats when forcibly confronted.
然而，你们未能向我证明
However, you have failed to demonstrate to me
你们的哲学之间有任何其他区别
any other difference between your philosophies.
你的善和恶用同样的手段
Your good and your evil use the same methods,
达到相同的结果
achieve the same results.
你有什么解释吗？
Do you have an explanation?
你制定了方法和目标
You established the methods and the goals.
供你选择使用
For you to use as you chose.
如果他们赢了，你给他们什么？
What did you offer the others if they won?
他们最想要的
What they wanted most.
力量
Power.
你给了我我船员的生命
You offered me the lives of my crew.
我认为你赢得了他们的生命
I perceive you have won their lives.
你对多少人做过这样的事？
How many others have you done this to?
是什么让你有权决定生死？
What gives you the right to hand out life and death?
促使你来这里的同样的权利
The same right that brought you here.
了解新事物的需要
The need to know new things.
我们和平地来
We came in peace.
那你们可以和平地离开
And you may go in peace.
柯克呼叫企业号，进来
Kirk to Enterprise. Come in.
苏鲁：是你吗，舰长？
SULU: Is that you, Captain?
你们还好吗？
Are you all right?
是的，苏鲁先生，我们没事
Yes, Mr. Sulu, we're all right.
你可以把我们传送上船了
You may beam us aboard.
斯科特先生，报告
Mr. Scott, report.
飞船恢复正常运转了，长官
The ship is functioning normally again, sir,
重启循环正在运行
and the restart cycle is in operation.
看起来不像发生过故障
You'd never know anything had been out of order.
我无法理解
I can't fathom it.
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu.
我们应该在 30 分钟内启动曲速，长官
We should be on warp power within 30 minutes, sir.
很好，契科夫先生
Good. Mister Chekov.
护盾的衰减已停止并且正在自我修复
The deterioration in the shielding has stopped and is reversing itself.
我无法解释
I have no explanation.
谢谢你，契科夫先生
Thank you, Mr. Chekov.
史波克先生，有解释吗？
Mr. Spock. Any explanation?
猜想，而非解释
Conjecture, rather than explanation.
说说？
Well?
我们似乎被能够控制物质的生物的力量所束缚
It would seem that we were held in the power of creatures able to control matter
并以任何想要的方式重新排列分子
and to rearrange molecules in whatever fashion was desired.
所以他们能够创造出苏拉克和林肯的形象
So they were able to create images of Surak and Lincoln
在扫描了我们的大脑并使用同胞作为源材料后
after scanning our minds and using their fellow creatures as source matter.
他们看起来很真实
They seemed so real.
对我来说，尤其是林肯先生
And to me, especially Mr. Lincoln.
我觉得我真的见到了林肯
I feel I actually met Lincoln.
是的，还有苏拉克
Yes. And Surak.
也许，从某种意义上说，它们是真实的，舰长
Perhaps, in a sense, they were real, Captain.
既然他们是由我们自己的思想创造出来的
Since they were created out of our own thoughts,
怎么可能不是我们期望的那样呢？
how could they be anything but what we expected them to be?
看到他再次死去，我很难过
It was so hard for me to see him die again.
我觉得我理解了地球为实现最后的和平所必须经历的事情
I feel I understand what Earth must have gone through to achieve final peace.
柯克舰长，这颗星球恢复了正常外观
Captain Kirk, the planet has resumed its normal appearance.
他们在银河系中还有很多工作要做，史波克
There is still so much of their work to be done in the galaxy, Spock.
苏鲁先生，让我们脱离轨道，继续我们的下一个任务
Mr. Sulu, break us out of orbit and continue to our next assignment.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.